Hardhead has this fantastic tool built in called The Hard Hat Network
Hardhat 内置了一个很棒的工具叫做 "Hardhat Network"
hard hat comes built in with Hard Hat Network,
Hardhat 内置 Hardhat Network
a local Aetherium network node designed for development,
它是一个专为开发而设计的本地以太坊网络节点
akin to ganache, that allows you to deploy your contracts and run your tests and debug your code.
与 Ganache 相似，它允许你部署合约，运行测试以及调试代码
Whenever we run a command in hard hat, or a script and hard hat or a task and hard hat,
每当我们在 Hardhat 中运行命令、脚本或者任务时
we by default deploy to this fake Hard Hat Network.
我们都是默认部署到这个虚拟的 Hardhat Network
This Hard Hat Network is very similar to ganache,
这个 Hardhat Network 与 Ganache 十分相似
except for instead of having this UI,
除了没有这个 UI 界面
it runs in the background for our scripts.
它在我们脚本的后台中运行
In fact, if we go to our hard hat.config.js,
事实上，如果我们打开 "hardhat.config.js"
we can scroll down to the bottom to this module that exports section
我们可以滑倒底部找到这个 "module.exports" 部分
and add more information about our default networks.
并添加有关默认网络的更多信息
So right now, if we don't have anything in this module that export,
现在，如果我们在 "module.exports" 中没有任何相关信息
by default, it adds this piece called default network hardhat.
那么默认情况下，它就会添加 "defaultNetwork: 'hardhat'"
So anytime we run a script,
所以无论我们什么时候运行脚本
without specifying a network, it automatically uses this fake Hard Hat Network.
只要没有特别指定某个网络，它都会自动使用这个虚拟的 Hardhat Network
And this fake Hard Hat Network
并且这个虚拟的 Hardhat Network
comes automatically with an RPC URL and a private key for you.
会自动为你提供一个 "RPC URL" 和一个私钥
So you don't even have to add one in.
所以你不必再额外添加一个了
This is one of the major advantages of working with Hardhead.
这是使用 Hardhat 工作的主要优势之一
It just automatically gives you this fake blockchain. And these fake private keys,
它会自动为你提供一个虚拟区块链以及虚拟私钥
if you want to be a little bit more explicit. And I always recommend being more explicit,
如果你想让这里更明确一些，并且我也认为明确一点会比较好
we can add the default network in to the module that are experts.
那么可以在 "module.exports" 中添加一下 "defaultNetwork"
So now our default network is explicitly stated as hard hat.
所以现在我们的 "defaultNetwork" 被明确指定为 "hardhat"
However, in any script, you run,
不过，无论任何脚本，你都可以在运行时
you can choose whatever network you want to work with.
选择你想要使用的任意网络
So if I want to explicitly say
所以如果我想明确指定
I want to run our deploy script on our fake Hard Hat Network,
我想在虚拟的 Hardhat Network 上运行我们的部署脚本的话
I can do yarn, hard hat, run scripts, deploy dot j s, dash dash network, hard hat,
我可以这么做 "yarn hardhat run scripts/deploy.js --network hardhat"
this is us telling her that,
这就是我们在告诉 Hardhat
hey, we want to run this script on the Hard Hat Network.
嘿，我们要在 Hardhat Network 上运行这个脚本
Hopefully, you might be able to see where this is going.
希望你已经看明白这是怎么一回事了
Having this network flag
有了这个网络标识之后
makes it incredibly easy to switch across different chains, different block chains, different private keys, etc.
在不同链，不同区块链，不同私钥等等之间的切换就会变得非常容易
So we have our default network set the hard hat here,
现在我们把这里的 defaultNetwork 设置为了 hardhat
we can add other networks in here as well.
我们也可以在这里添加其它网络
The way we do that is we're going to add a networks section.
方法就是添加一个 "network" 部分
And we're going to define any of the network sections that we want.
并按照我们的需要定义它
And remember to put a comment there so that your Visual Studio code doesn't get mad at you.
记得这里要加个逗号，这样你的 Visual Studio Code 就不会向你报错了
So recently, we worked with Rigby so let's go ahead and add a Rinkeby network in here.
就近期来说，我们使用的是 Rinkeby，所以我们来添加一个 Rinkeby 网络
So we're gonna say another network is gonna be really
所以我要指定另外的网络是 "rinkeby"
cool. So I should just be able to change the network flag to Rigby now, right?
酷！所以我现在应该能够切换网络标识为 Rinkeby 了，对吧？
Well, not quite.
好吧，并不是
If you try to run that,
如果你尝试运行，
you're gonna get invalid value undefined for hardhat config networks. Rigby, that URL,
就会得到 “无效的未定义值 HardhatConfig.networks.rinkeby.url”
it's expecting you to tell it, hey, what the URL is,
它希望你能告诉它，嘿，这是什么 URL
since this isn't the hard hat network,
因为这并不是 Hardhat Network
we need to tell hard hat exactly how we're going to connect to rink B.
所以我们需要告诉 hardhat 如何链接到 Rinkeby
And this is where a lot of what we learned before is going to come in handy, again,
这就是我们之前学到的许多知识再次派上用场的地方了
exactly the same as what we did before.
就和我们之前做的完全一样
We're going to create a new Dotty v file, and we're going to add our Rigby URL in this dot env file.
我们要创建一个新的 ".env" 文件，并在其中添加 "rinkeby URL"
Just remember, dot env is an r dot get ignore just in case.
记住 ".env" 要放到 ".gitignore" 里以防万一
So in our Dotty env, we're going to add that RPC URL from alcmi back in here
所以在 ".env" 里，我们要从 alchemy 添加相应的 "RPC URL"
before we just said RPC URL. But since we might want to work across multiple networks,
在指定 "RPC URL" 之前，由于我们可能要在多个网络上工作
it's usually good to specify exactly what network each URL stands for.
所以通常最好是确切指定每个 URL 对应的具体网络
So we're gonna say Rynkeby RPC URL equals and then paste that URL in here.
所以我们要输入 "RINKEBY_RPC_URL = " 然后把 URL 粘贴到这里
Now, as you probably have guessed,
现在，你可能已经猜到了
we can add our URL to our Rinkeby network here.
我们要把 URL 添加给这里的 rinkeby 网络
for readability, I usually like to add them as variables right above the module that experts.
为了可读性，我通常喜欢把它们添加为变量，放到 "module.exports" 上方
So I'll say const Rynkeby. RPC URL equals process dot E and V dot Rynkeby RPC URL.
所以就是 "const RINKEBY_RPC_URL = process.env.RINKEBY_RPC_URL"
And once again, we're going to be pulling that Rinckey RPC URL from our environment variable.
再次提醒一下，我们将从环境变量中获取 "RINKEBY_RPC_URL"
Of course, in order to pull that environment variable in,
当然，为了获取这个环境变量
we're going to need to use that dot env package again.
我们需要再次调用那个 "dotenv" 包
So to add that in, we're going to yarn add dash dash dev dot EMV.
要想添加它，我们要做的就是 "yarn add --dev dotenv"
And at the top of our Hardhead config,
然后在 "hardhat.config.js" 的顶部
we're going to add require dot EMV,
我们要添加 "require("dotenv")"
and then do dot config to enable the config.
然后加上 ".config()" 以启动配置
Now this means we should be able to pull our rink the RPC URL from our dot env.
Now that we have that in our Rinkeby network,
现在我们已经有了 Rinkeby 网络
we can add URL Rinckey RPC URL. Awesome.
我们就可以添加 "url: RINKEBY_RPC_URL"
So we have an RPC URL for different network.
所以现在我们就有了一个不同网络的 "RPC URL"
But what else do we usually need?
但我们还需要什么？
Well, we usually need a private key to work with an actual network,
通常来说我们还需要为真实的网络提供一个私钥
or that doesn't automatically give us a private key for rugby,
Hardhat 不会自动为我们提供用于 Rinkeby 的私钥
because Hardhead can't just give us test and the Etherium,
因为 Hardhat 不能直接提供测试网的以太币
we need to have an actual account an actual test nets.
我们需要在真实的测试网络上有一个实际的账户
Hardhead doesn't control those. So we have to actually give it a real URL and a real private key.
Hardhat 不能提供这些，所以我们要为它提供一个真实的 URL 以及私钥
So to add private keys, you actually add something called accounts,
要添加私钥，你需要添加一个 "account"
you add a list of accounts that you want to give to hard hat
并添加一个你想提供给 Hardhat 的一个账户列表
for us, we're only going to add one, which is going to be our private key.
对我们来说，只添加一个就好，这就是我们的私钥
And for our private key, we're going to do the exact same thing.
对于私钥，我们要做的事情完全相同
We're gonna say const private key equals process dot e NV dot private key.
就是 "const PRIVATE_KEY = process.env.PRIVATE_KEY"
And since this private key is going to be a real private key for a real test net,
因为这个私钥是一个存在于真实测试网络上的一个真正的私钥
again, we are going to have to grab this from our meta mask.
所以我们必须要从 MetaMask 中获取它
So it will go to our meta mask, three dots, account details, export private key,
所以我们打开 MetaMask，点这三个点，账户详情，导出私钥
and we'll add our password in here.
在这里输入我们的密码
And then in our dot env will add private key
接着在 ".env" 里添加 "PRIVATE_KEY = "
equals and then add our private key.
最后添加我们的私钥
Now I know I've said this 100 times, but please, please, please,
我知道我已经说了 100 遍了，但是请，请，请
for learning this, do not use a real key that is connected to any real money
在学习这个的时候，不要使用任何与真钱有关联的私钥
just in case, please use a new meta mask.
以防万一，请使用一个新的 MetaMask
I've know I've said it a bunch. But some people go no, I'm going to be okay, I'll be safe.
我知道我说过很多遍了，但还是有些人会说，我没事，我很安全
Just to be super, super safe here, please use a brand new meta mask.
但为了确保绝对安全，请使用一个全新的 MetaMask
So now that we have a private key,
所以现在我们有了一个私钥
we're going to add it in here account private key.
我们要把它放到这里 "account: [PRIVATE_KEY]"
And now we have an account here.
现在我们在这里就有了一个账户了
One more thing I like to do is I like to give the chain ID of the network,
还有一件我常做的事是，我喜欢提供网络的 "chainID"
which for Rigby is going to be for
对 Rinkeby 来说就是 4
every single EVM base network as a new chain ID
每一个 EVM 基础网络都有一个新的 chainID
and EVM network basically just means solidity works on it. This includes all test nets,
EVM 网络的意思就是 Solidity 可以在其上面运行，这包括了所有的测试网络
there's a good site called chainless.org, which may or may not be going down at some point,
有一个很好用的网站叫做 "chainlist.org"，有的时候可能会上不去
it has a list of all these different networks.
它在列表中列出了所有这些不同的网络
For example, you can see on here a theory main net has a chain ID of one
比如说，你可以看到以太网主网络的 chainID 是 1
byte and smart chain is 56, avalanches, 4311 for
"Binance Smart Chain" 是 56，"Avalanche" 是 43114
Phantom, opera 250, Polygon, 137, etc.
"Fantom Opera" 是 250，"Polygon" 是 137 等等等等
Each one of these EVM compatible chains has their own chain ID, rank V, the chain ID is for
每个 EVM 兼容链都有自己的 chainID，Rinkeby 的 chainID 是 4
adding the chain ID is helpful here for later on. And we'll get to that in the future.
添加 chainID 有助于之后的一些操作，将来我们会涉及到这一点
But for now, just go ahead and make sure to add your chain IDs.
但现在只需要确保添加你的 chainID 即可。
Okay, now that we have the RPC URL, we have the private key,
好了，现在我们有了 "RPC URL" 和私钥
we can go ahead and test deploying this to an actual test net,
就可以继续在实际的测试网上测试部署了
and actually did something incorrect
here. And we're gonna get an error here. And I want you to go
ahead and try to figure out and debug this error yourself.
You're ready. Alright, let's do it. We'll do yarn, hard hat, run
scripts, deploy dot j s, dash dash network Rinkeby. And we get
this wonderfully weird error, which we see we have deployed
contract. So we know that in our deploy script, we get to at
least this line, but then we're getting an error, I highly
likely hear what's going on saying cannot read properties
have no reading send transaction, if you want, you
can absolutely go to this spot. But it basically it looks like
it's having a hard time understanding what the private
key or what the account of this is. And what do you think I'm
going to recommend we do? Well, if it's not clear, after doing a
little bit of triaging and debugging, we're going to copy
this air. And we're going to come on over to Google and paste
that right in. It looks like we do get a question here from
stackexchange Etherium. And it looks like it's really similar
to what we're doing. We scroll down. They're running nearly the
exact same script that we're running, they're using MPX
instead of yarn. They've got a pretty minimalistic deploy file.
Let's scroll down and see what the answers have to say. I've
seen this error where my private key wasn't properly populated. I
would also use an environment variable I'm pretty sure Are
environment variables good. But we have a second one saying in
your heart head, I can think that Jas, it should be accounts
instead of account, it works for me, let's go back to our head
config and see if that's what's going on. Uh huh, we put account
in this should be accounts. So let's swap that over to
accounts. We'll clear our terminal. And we'll run this
again. Uh huh. And now it's reading a little bit longer,
which is good. This means that we're probably deploying this to
rink B, which is what we want to see. Awesome. And now we can see
deployed contract to, and we have a contract address here. So
we'll grab this contract. And we'll pop on over to bring the
ether scan, that's numbering the ether scan. And we'll go ahead
and we'll paste this in. Awesome. And we see our contract
was created about 26 seconds ago. Perfect. Now for this part,
you don't have to deploy this to rink be with me, if you follow
along here. That's good enough. So remember, the flying to test
that's can take a long time. So for this one, you don't have to
deploy with me.